Patrick Ng

Background & Objective

Web developer extremely experienced in HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, responsive web design, UI development, front-end techniques including progressive enhancement, semantics, and usability. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, RSpec testing, a working knowledge of Angular.js, and basic Linux-based environment server administration.

Skills & Qualifications

HTML5 / CSS3 / jQuery Progressive enhancement UI Prototype & Development Responsive design Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop Ruby on Rails / Node.js Git/SVN version control AngularJS/Ember.js API design Linux server administration

Experience

UI DEVELOPER Nov 2013 - Present

E*TRADE Financial, New York, NY

- Integrated front-end workflows for a new team
- Used Grunt.js with a static site generator extensively to populate and build templates
- Extensively used LESS and SASS preprocessors for OOCSS
- Created mock API / random JSON generator with node.js, express.js, and chance.js
- Extract and refactor WET code into DRY, reusable UI components for rapid prototyping
- Maintain and construct responsive prototypes with AngularJS, Ember.js, Twitter Bootstrap, Foundation, and Modernizr
- Fixed time sensitive bugs in production widgets by practicing TDD with Jasmine, Mocha, and Karma
- Set up staging server using Ubuntu and nginx to support and proxy to static sites, PHP, node.js, and Unicorn/Puma served Rails applications
- Implemented processes monitoring with forever, monit, and upstart
- Automated deployment process with Mina deploy scripts

INTERACTIVE DEVELOPER

Aug 2013 - Nov 2013

ExpandTheRoom, New York, NY

- Built proof of concept web applications with KnockoutJS, AngularJS, & MEAN stack
- Maintain and apply bug fixes to mobile applications using Titanium Studio
- Created microsites with HTML5 and CSS3 animations

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb 2013 - Nov 2013

Tealeaf Academy, http://gotealeaf.com

- Aiding the primary instructor in the Introduction to Ruby and Web Development and Rapid Prototyping with Ruby on Rails courses
- Helping students with code problems and homework assignments

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Oct 2012 - Nov 2013

Self-employed, Brooklyn, NY

- Using Ruby on Rails, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3 for client projects
- RSpec testing
- Background jobs
- SEO best practices
- Grunt + Bower workflow

FREELANCE DEVELOPER

Dec 2012 - Feb 2013

ExpandTheRoom, New York, NY

- Contributed to two mobile application projects with Titanium Studio
- Extracted out XHR service layer to modularize applications
- Implemented web experience to complement a specific mobile application

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Wonder | visualizing brands, a division of Sandow Media, New York, NY

Mar 2012 - Sept 2012

- Built sites for different brands using Twitter Bootstrap, HTML5 Boilerplate, CSS3, and jQuery
- Ensured that sites gracefully degraded to usable state and supported sites in IE 7+, Opera, Chrome, Safari and Firefox
- Prototyped layouts with grid systems from wireframes
- Integrated SASS into project workflow
- Used CSS3 media queries to build responsive websites and integrated custom jQuery code for different screen resolutions
- Customized and implemented a web based HTML5 Canvas drawing tool with JavaScript
- Used git to track updates and merge changes for use on development, staging and production servers

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Educational Networks, New York, NY

Jan 2006 - Feb 2012

- Helped customers over the phone regarding help with daily maintenance of websites
- Conducted daily web site and MYSQL database editing and tune-ups
- Converted Adobe PSD files into standards-based HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery
- Built sites with emphasis on Section 508 web accessibility
- Sliced well over 600 websites and integrated with SchoolSitePro CMS software using JSP syntax
- Expert in progressive enhancement (graceful degradation) of websites to support the latest HTML5/CSS3 features
- Made design changes to PSDs and produced graphical mockups through grids and wire-framing
- Handled all requests and tickets pertaining to code conflicts and subtle cross-browser nuances including Internet Explorer 6-9, Firefox, Chrome, Opera & Safari
- Redesigned outdated modules into table-less format with pure CSS

Education References

Build Production Quality Applications Tealeaf Academy, February 2013

Rapid Prototyping with Ruby on Rails Tealeaf Academy, September 2012

Bachelor of Science in Business, Management & Finance Brooklyn College, Brooklyn, NY, December 2010 Dean's List, Fall 2010 References gladly furnished upon request